(北朝鲜,两年前)
让我回家,我只是单纯的生意人
SALT: Please let me go home. Please, I'm not who you think I am.
我真的不是你们想的那种人
I'm really not who you think I am.
拜托,我不是特务
PIease. PIease. I'm not a spy.
- 你是特务 - 求求你,我不是特务
MAN: You are a spy. I'm not a spy.
求你让我回家吧
Please let me go home.
来一次
Try again.
我不是间谍,我是生意人
I am not a spy. I am a businesswoman.
我是润克石油的员工
I work for Rink Petroleum and Gas.
请跟他们联络,润克石油
Please call them. I work for Rink Petroleum.
你是来破坏我们的核子设施的
You are here to sabotage our nuclear ambitions. Yes?.
我不是特务!我不是特务!
I am not a spy!. I am not a spy!.
- 重来一次 - 我不是特务!
Try again. I am not a spy.
- 你是特务 - 我不是特务!
You are a spy. I am not a spy.
别撒谎
Don't Iie to me!.
我不是特务
I am not a spy.
由于我亲爱领袖的
MAN 1 [OVER SPEAKER]: It is through the grace and munificence
英明与宽容
of our glorious Dear Leader
朝鲜民主主义人民共和国...
that the Democratic People 's Republic of Korea
赦免美国帝国主义者
has pardoned the American imperialist
对我社会主义国家采取的敌对行为
for her hostile acts against our socialist nation.
压低头,交换前别说一句话
Keep your head down. Don't say anything till we make the swap.
以防金正日改变心意
I n case Kim Jong ll here changes his mind.
交换
Exchange.
向右转
MAN 2: Right face!.
Right face!.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你不懂什么?
You don't understand what?.
所有指示都说要丢下我
All the rules say to leave me, that one life
不值得为一个人暴露组织行动
is not worth blowing operational cover.
你没搞错
You got that right.
必要时,我们会为大我牺牲小我
If we have to lose someone for the greater good, we will.
那为什么救我?
So why did you do it?
我没救你
Well, I didn't do it.
是他
He did.
他一发现你下落,就拼命设法救你
Once he found out where you were, there was no stopping him.
他向国会议员、国务院请愿
He petitioned the Senate, the State Department.
我们不要媒体注目,所以我们想
We didn't need the publicity so I figured we better do something
再不设法,他会自己进攻这个烂国家
or he's gonna invade this goddamn rice-paddy republic himself.
你还好吧?
You okay?.
还好
Yeah.
特 工 绍 特
(华盛顿,现在)
早安
Good morning.
结婚纪念日快乐
Happy anniversary.
要我帮你准备早餐吗?
You want me to make you breakfast?
吃松饼如何?
How about pancakes?
你亲手做?
Your cooking?
开玩笑,你很爱吃我做的
You're joking. You like my cooking.
德国人不开玩笑的
Germans don't joke.
波特喜欢我的料理
Burt likes my cooking.
把你的虫收起来
Get your bugs off the table.
- 这是蜘蛛 - 蜘蛛就是虫
They're spiders. They're bugs.
这是蜘蛛
MlKE: They're spiders.
蜘蛛就是虫
SALT: They're bugs.
把下层向前两个一样折回来
WOMAN [ON VIDEO]: Fold the next layer back as you did the two before it.
把餐巾转过来
Turn the napkin over.
将两端向后折
Fold both sides back,
在三分之一的地方重复
and over one another about a third of the way.
检查是否对称,再仔细折妥
Check for symmetry and press the fold down well.
你上班时间搞这个?
Are you doi ng this on company time?
今天是我结婚纪念日
And insert your favorite silverware... It's my anniversary.
我要一切完美
And I want it to be perfect.
不过
But
这并不性感
that is not sexy.
对,不过这很实用
No, but it is utilitarin.
这年头实用就代表性感
And utilitarian is the new sexy.
确定身份了,他叫乌珊奥萨耶夫
I ran the trace. First name Usam, last name Utsaev.
- 确实线索? - 有一个
Any verifiable hits? One.
法兰西斯,帮个忙
Hey, Francis, do me a favor
把报告锁好,明天再说
and stick that in the safe till tomorrow.
这位女神今晚有大事要办
Mata Hari here's got a big night tonight.
是,长官,马上办
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
长官?
WlNTER: "Sir""?.
我的样子有那么专横吗?
Do I look like a '"sir"' to you?
官架子十足
From head to toe.
我很惊讶他没叫你"陛下"
I'm surprised he didn't call you ""Your Majesty."'
我喜欢这个称呼
I like the ring of that.
我想我喜欢人家叫我"陛下"
I think I'd prefer "'Your Majesty.""
我以前也这么嫩吗?
Was I ever that young?
比他更嫩
Younger.
陪我出去
Walk me out.
总统办公室的简报如何?
SALT: How did the Oval Office briefing go?
你知道的,跟往常一样
Oh, you know. The usual.
总统想知道俄罗斯事件的详情
President wants to know what's happening in Russia
你呢?听说面谈很顺利
the day before it happens. How about you?. I heard that interview went well.
老天保佑
Fingers crossed.
你确定要换位子?
You sure about this?
一旦去做行政人员就不能回头了
You know, once you start pushing paper, there's no turning back.
我上次出任务时有个超怪的感觉
I had the strangest feeling when I was out last time.
我得了思乡病
I was homesick.
思乡病?不能吃药解决吗?
WlNTER: Homesick?
长官!长官!
Can't you take something for that?. Sir!. Sir!.
有卧底来自首,十分钟前
We got a walk-in. A defector, 1 0 minutes ago.
在这里?
Here?.
我猜他不相信我们的伪装
I guess he's not buying our cover.
查过背景了?
Did you get his bona fides?. He's Russian.
俄罗斯人,只宣称是前国安局探员
He says he's FSB but won't give us any more.
他很怪
He's a strange guy.
他英文如何?
How's his English?
还可以
Passable. Not great.
但是没办法很清楚的表达
But if it got down to the subtleties of English nuance...
泰德,麦克在家等我
Ted, Mike's gonna be waiting for me.
对,我也要赶飞机
Yeah, and I got a plane to catch.
来吧,莎特
Come on, Salt.
没有坏人能逃过你的法眼
No one can sort out a nutjob from the real thing faster than you.
我只有25分钟
I got 25 minutes.
我有26分,走吧
I got 26. Let's go.
好吧,等我们有进展再决定
PEABODY: Yeah, okay. Well, we'll decide when we know more.
是谁找反情报组的?
Who called Counterintelligence? Not me.
不是我
Hey, Ted.
我们不请自来
We're crashing the party.
皮巴帝
Peabody.
莎特
Salt.
取下头套
MAN: PIease remove the hood.
麦克风打开
Microphones are on.
检查读数
WOMAN: Checking levels.
基准确定
Bseline recorded.
启动神经扫瞄,准备好了
Neural scan is up. Ready to go.
伊芙
Ev. Mm.
好
Yeah.
开始录音录像
MAN: Commencing audio and visual recording.
测试耳机
[OVER EARPlECE] Testing earpiece.
会谈开始时间14点42分
Interview has commenced at 1 442.
你结婚了
You're married.
对于一个女特务来说
A husband must be a distraction
丈夫是个绊脚石
for a female intelligence officer.
我们要谈的是你
Well, we're here to talk about you.
你叫什么名字?
So, what is your name?
我叫
My name is
欧拉维席奥洛夫
Oleg Vassilyevich Orlov.
我得了癌症
I have cancer.
我真感动
I'm moved.
一个投诚的癌症病患
A defector with cancer.
你是想卖情报换化疗?
Are you selling secrets for chemo
还是你只是怕死?
or are you afraid of dying?
要说我的行动会得到什么报应
If I have gained anything by damning myself,
就是我不再恐惧
it is that I no longer have anything to fear.
俄罗斯也正面临死亡
Russia is also dying.
不过不像我,她还没死
But unlike me, she's not dead.
欧拉维席奥洛夫
Oleg Vassily Orlov,
1993年出现于新西伯利亚
shows up in 1 993 in Novosibirsk Oblast, Siberia.
是前情报头子维多的手下
He was on Victor Barisovsky's staff there.
他是国安局的人
WlNTER: He checks out as FSB, Ev.
扫瞄显示癌症的事他没说谎
Scan says he's truthful on the cancer.
93年以前呢?
Prior to '93?.
俄罗斯原本强大
ORLOV: Russia was once strong, poWerful...
啥都没有
Nothing.
他根本不存在
He doesn't eXist.
等一切回复原本正确的轨道
ORLOV: And she Will be again when things have been set back
她也将再度强大
on the correct path.
我有别的地方要去,奥洛夫先生
I have somewhere I need to be, Mr. Orlov,
不介意的话,请切入重点
so if you wouldn't mind getting to the point.
我来是要告诉你一个故事
[IN RUSSlAN] I came here to tell you a story.
我不喜欢听故事
[IN RUSSlAN] I don't like stories.
不过我还是会听的
But I'll listen anyway.
请说英文
[IN ENGLlSH] In English, please.
其他人也在听
Others are listening.
1975年
[IN ENGLlSH] 1 975.
冷战时期
The Cold War.
在格洛斯尼一个体育馆里
In a gymnasium in Grozny,
一位苏联的奥运摔角选手
a Soviet Olympic wrestler
沙夏宣科夫
named Sasha Fyorodovich Chenkov
初次邂逅
meets for the first time
当代唯一女性西洋棋大师
the only female chess grand master of her era;
安雅纽伦科娃
Anka Nurekyova.
一个月内,他们就闪电结婚了
Within a month, they Were married.
然后一年内,生了一个孩子
And within a year, a child.
一个月后
One month more,
那孩子被送回原来出生的医院
the child was back in the same hospital,
高烧病重
sick with fever.
之后过了几天
And within days after that,
那孩子突然死了
the child suddenly was dead.
对,有个孩子死了
Yes, a child Was dead.
对,有个孩子被埋葬了
And, yes, a child was buried.
不过宣科夫的孩子还活着
But the Chenkov baby Was alive
变成了另一个人的资产
and became the property of another man.
这位特务大师设计一个伟大计划
A master spy Who had devised the greatest plan
一个爱国志士的终极计划
a Russian patriot could ever invent.
摧毁美国的计划
A plan to destroy America.
一切始于...
It had all started
一位美国人
with an American
李哈维奥斯华
named Lee Harvey Oswald.
1959年,他移民到俄国
In 1 959, he emigrated to Russia.
三年后,他返回了家乡
Three years later, he returned home.
不过回到美国的那个人
But the man who came back to America
事实上,是一位叫亚列克的特务
was in fact a Russian spy named Alek.
在1963年11月22日
On November 22nd, 1 963,
亚列克成为新计划第一位成功者
Alek became the first success of the neW program
(刺客暗杀总统)
也成为苏维埃联邦的英雄
and a hero of the Soviet Union.
这位特务大师因此得到允许
The spymaster Was now given the go-ahead
创造更多像亚列克的人
to create many more like Alek.
一批特务大军,有男有女
Scores of agents, males and females,
用来顶替美国人
to be substituted for Americans.
我宣誓效忠国旗
CH I LDREN : I pledge allegiance to the flag...
在一座废弃的修道院中
At an abandoned monastery,
宣科夫和大家早在学会俄文之前
Chenkov and other boys and girls learned English
就一起学习英文
Iong before they learned Russian.
熟悉成语
Drilled in idiom,
文化特质,还有
idiosyncrasy and
意识型态
ideology.
透过严格的体能锻炼
And by methods of rigorous physical
以及心理教育
and psychological programming,
这位特务大师制造出钢铁大军
the spymaster made warriors of iron.
绝对服从、意志刚强
Unquestioning and unbreakable.
谁先到?
MAN : Who crossed first?.
谁最后到?
Who crossed last?
你快急死我了
You're killing me, man.
好心的仙女什么时候出现?
When does the good fairy come in?
没有
Never.
这是个没有希望的故事
It's a story without hope.
宣科夫被派去替代
Chenkov was matched with the child of
一个美国家庭的孩子
a visiting American family.
出了一场意外,那家人都死了
There was an accident. The family died.
宣科夫被送去美国
Chenkov was sent to America
活在一个谎言之中
to live a complete lie
耐心等待从内部发动攻击的那一天
and to patiently await the day to attack from within.
毁灭日
Day X.
等待已久的任务
The long-awaited mission
终于到了
is here.
宣科夫将会前去纽约市
Chenkov will travel to New York City
狙杀俄罗斯总统
to kill the president of Russia
就在美国副总统的告别式上
at the funeral of the American vice president.
宣科夫就是KA12
Chenkov is KA 1 2.
"KA"…
""KA.""
冷战时期的传说
Cold War legend.
训练精良的俄罗斯潜伏特务
Highly trained Russian sleeper agents
潜入美国社会中搞破坏和暗杀
inserted into American society to sabotage and assassinate.
传说会等上数年甚至数十年才行动
Supposedly they'd wait years to strike. Decades, even.
传说
Mm. Supposedly.
你不相信有潜伏的特务?
What, you don't believe in moles?. I believe in moles, all right.
我相信,只是不相信瞎扯
Just not the bogeyman.
特别是说要毙掉他们自己的总统
Especially if the plan is to kill their own president.
这家伙在卖假情报
This guy's selling smoke.
结束吧,伊芙
Wrap it up, Ev.
你说俄罗斯特务要杀俄罗斯总统?
SALT: So a Russian agent is going to kill the Russian president?.
就这样?
Is that it?
好吧
Mm-hm. Okay.
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
你希望能获得什么报酬?
And what would you like in return for that information?
我只想帮助你去做
I simply wish to help you do
你要做的事
what you need to do.
你很行
You're good.
KA计划很唬人
The KA program is brilliant bullshit.
不过我已经下班了
But I'm officially off duty,
你可以把剩下的胡编跟我同事讲
so you can tell the rest of your little story to one of my colleagues.
莎特
Salt.
什么?
Yes?.
那位俄罗斯特务的名字叫莎特
The name of the Russian agent is Salt.
伊芙莎特
Evelyn Salt.
我就叫伊芙莎特
My name is Evelyn Salt.
那你就是俄国间谍
Then you are a Russian spy.
实话
WOMAN [OVER EARPlECE]: Truthful.
目前为止的扫瞄显示他说的一切
So far the fMRI scan registers truthful
都是真的
on everything he"s said.
泰德?
Ted?.
通知保安组,要他们找我丈夫
Call Protective Services, make sure they find my husband.
我要打电话
I need to get to the phone.
不行,这种扫瞄结果下不行
Not after the neural scan.
就因为他没发抖?我也能骗过机器
I can beat that thing five times out of six.
我受过训,他也一样
I am trained to, and so is he.
我需要我的手机,我要打给我丈夫
I need my phone. I need to call my husband.
- 让我联络我丈夫 - 让我看看
Let me call my husband. Let me see it.
他提到我的结婚戒指是有原因的
There's a reason he mentioned my wedding ring, Ted.
他们掀间谍的底,不会只掀一面
They don't just blow up their cover
他们会掀个彻底,你很清楚
they blow up their whole cover life. You know that.
记得亨利老婆的遭遇吧?
Do you remember Henley's wife?
我记得
Yes, I do.
用免提
Speaker.
请在讯号声之后留话,谢谢
MlKE [ON RECORDlNG]: Please leave a message after the tone. Thanks. Bye.
老公,是我,听到马上回电
Honey, it's me. Please call me as soon as you get this.
好吗?一听到我的留言就回电
Okay, sweetheart? As soon as you get this.
祝你马到成功,宣科夫同志
ORLOV: Godspeed, Comrade Chenkov.
找人来讯问那个混蛋
Someone interrogate that piece of shit.
找个够凶的来
Someone who enjoys getting answers.
听着,伊芙,保持冷静
Look, Ev, try to stay calm.
我不是俄国间谍
I'm not a goddamn Russian spy.
我没说你是
I didn't say you were.
到我办公室把这事解决
Let's go up to my office, we can sort this out.
我们要去个安全的地方
No, no. We gotta go to a secure location. Now.
好吧
WlNTER: All right.
这里比任何地方都安全
Doesn't get any more secure than this.
伊芙?
Ev?
五分钟
Five minutes.
联络保安组要他们找到麦克
Call Protective Services, find Mike. I will.
这根本是瞎扯
This is bullshit.
等一下,我们马上进去
Give us a sec, we'll be right in.
我知道接下来归你管
I know we're heading into your jurisdiction.
- 我只求你给我五分钟 - 不行
I'm just asking for five minutes. No.
你不能单独跟她谈,我要跟她谈
If I have to. You can't have five minutes. I have to talk to her.
她吓坏了,你没看到吗?
She's scared. Don't you see that?
我无所谓
I don't care.
俄罗斯小组有内奸,我很确定
There is a mole in Russia house, Ted. There is a mole. I am sure.
请走进电梯
PIease step in the elevator.
事关俄罗斯总统
PEABODY: --Russian president, okay?
我必须请你不要插手此
So I'm gonna ask you to step out of my way.
怎么回事?
What the hell is that?
长官
Sir.
我得上厕所
I gotta pee.
他跑哪去了?
MAN 1 [OVER RADIO]: Where do you think he went?
前门没人看到他
MAN 2 [OVER RADIO]: No one saw him coming out the front.
老天爷
Wl NTER: Jesus Christ. Here he is again.
没迹象显示他在外面
No sign of him so far on the street.
这是两分钟前,封锁前的影像
It's two minutes ago, before lockdown.
有他的清晰影像吗?
Anything clean on him?.
刚找到一张
We just got a match, sir.
1981年5月拍摄
It's May Day, 1 981.
有布里兹涅夫,还有...
There's Brezhnev. And there...
奥洛夫
Orlov. That's him.
他以前曾经是一号人物
PEABODY: He used to be a heavyweight once upon a time.
把照片送出去,每个票亭
Get that photo out. Every ticket counter,
机场、车站...布下天罗地网
airport, train station, taxi dispatcher, the whole nine yards.
帮我用机密专线联络悔孚局长
Get me Medford on a secure line.
是,长官
Yes, sir.
右上方屏幕,是即时影像?
Top-right screen. Is that live?.
是的
WOMAN 1 : Yes, sir.
她去哪了?快找她
Where is she going? Track her.
不准任何人离开大楼
WOMAN 2 [OVER SPEAKER]: No one may leave the building.
润克石油,警卫室
Rink Petroleum, Security.
你左边有一位女性,在你后面
Yes, you have a woman to your left,behind you.
伊芙莎特
Evelyn Salt.
她不见了
MAN: We lost the visual on her.
该死,她去哪了?
Damn it. Where'd she go?
目前因安全因素封锁
WOMAN 2: We are on security lockdoWn.
戴维?我是伊芙,麦克在吗?
Dave?. It"s Evelyn, is Mike there?.
不在,他吃完午饭就走了
MAN [OVER PHONE]: No, I'm sorry. He left after lunch.
祝结婚周年快乐
Hey, happy anniversary, huh?
楼梯
WOMAN 1 : The stairwell.
二楼
Second floor.
那楼有什么?
What's on that floor?
空的,是安全缓冲楼层
It's empty, a security buffer.
隔离封锁
Isolate and seal it.
把她的档案传到我手机上
Get her records to my handheld.
东走廊
WOMAN 1 : East corridor.
通知华府警方
Notifying Metropolitan Police.
切断电梯门电源
Kill the power to the elevator doors.
困住她了
We got her.
封锁所有楼层
MAN 1 [OVER RADIO]: Locking down all floors.
保安组启动威胁处理机制
MAN 2: Security Protective Service responding to threat.
找一队人到南楼梯井跟我会合
All right. Get a tactical team to meet me on the south stairwell.
是,长官
MAN 3: Y es, sir.
梅孚局长在线上
MAN 4: Director Medford, sir.
给我一把手枪
PEABODY: Get me a side arm.
我会再回她电话
I'll call her back.
该死
Shit.
不见了
MAN 3: Lost visual.
她人呢?快说啊
Where is she, Albert? Talk to me.
快点
Come on.
北走廊
WOMAN 1 : North hallway.
在那,讯问室,接上来
There, interrogation room, bring it up.
(职位:俄国小组秘密特务)
(目前身份:润克石油副总)
(特殊技能:近身搏击、爆破)
(双亲死于车祸,1988年12月)
(北朝鲜事件后与德国人麦克结婚)
转换频道
MAN: Switch down, switch down.
你找到他没?
Have you found him?
你这是在干什么?
WlNTER: What the hell are you doing, Ev?
这样不好
This doesn't look good.
MAN 1 :我们开始。 MAN 2: 拍摄。
MAN 1 : Let's do it. MAN 2: Move.
机动小组30秒内就会找上你
There's a tac team coming at you in 30 seconds.
把监视器上的内裤拿掉
Get your panties off the camera.
让我们看见你,你才不会有事
Get where We can see you so you don't get hurt.
你找到我丈夫没?
Have you found my husband?
这些人不是玩假的
These boys aren't fooling around.
你不跟我谈,我帮不了你
Please. I can't help you unless you talk to me.
等你找到麦克再打给我
Call me when you find Mike.
通过电梯外的走廊
MAN 3: SWeeping corridors outside the elevator.
戴上面具
MAN 4: Put the masks on.
情况很危险
MAN 5: Situation is hot.
将门打开2英尺,准备用瓦斯
Open the door about tWo feet. We 're gonna gas her.
人员就位,静待指示
WOMAN : T ac team in position. Waiting for a go.
有必要这么做吗?
Is that absolutely necessary?
怎么?你要我对她开火?
What, you want me to shoot her?
叫医疗小组待命
Get a medical team in place now.
待命中
We're ready.
行动
Now.
好,听我指令
Okay, on my count.
三、二、一
Three, two, one.
行动
Go.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
她人呢?动作快
Where is she? Come on, guys.
快找到她
Find her, Albert. Now.
嫌犯脱逃
MAN: Suspect has escaped.
那里,接上来
There. Bring that up.
盯着她,她要过街了
Stay with her, she's crossing the street.
移动监视器
Pan the goddamn camera.
倒转回去,放大影像
Back that up and zoom in.
我们找麦克克劳斯
WOMAN: We're looking for Michael Krause.
停
WlNTER: Freeze.
MAN 1 : 我们在找她的丈夫迈克。
MAN 1 : We're looking for her husband, Mike.
你这是在干什么?
What the hell are you doing, Ev?
WOMAN: 等等,那是什么时候? 不知道，无可奉告。
WOMAN: Wait, when was that?. No. No message.
MAN 2: 让我们切换到外部摄像机。
MAN 2: Let's switch to the exterior cameras.
麦克克劳斯一小时前离开办公室
Michael Krause left his office at the Smithsonian an hour ago.
莎特家离这里有20分钟
Salt"s apartment is 20 minutes away.
我们可以盯梢,不过她不会回去
We can cover it, but she won't go there.
她在乎麦克就会回去,别说出去
She will if she's serious about Mike. This stays in-house.
好
Okay.
出租车!
Taxi!
去U街,到了我会跟你说
U Street. I'll tell you when to stop.
我是麦克,请在讯号声之后留话
MlKE [ON RECORDlNG]: Hi, this is Mike. Please leave a message after the tone.
他是全球顶尖的节足动物学家
WlNTER: He's one of the world's top arachnologists, Ev,
因此他得以自由进出北朝鲜边界
and as such, enjoys pretty much unrestricted access to the borders of North Korea.
快恶补昆虫学,设法认识他吧
So brush up on your bugs and get to know him.
(蜘蛛,麦克克劳斯著)
他是我们的完美掩护
He's the perfect cover to get us inside.
麦克?
Mike?
老公?
Honey?
宝贝、宝贝
Hey, baby. Hey, baby.
没事了
It's all right. Shh.
没事,爸爸呢?
It's okay. Where's Daddy?.
爸爸呢?
Where's Daddy?.
来、来
Come on. Come on.
检查后门
MAN 1 : Check for back eXits.
快、快
Go!. Go!.
卧房,没问题
MAN 2: Bedroom, clear!.
厨房没问题
WOMAN: Kitchen is clear.
办公间,没问题
MAN 3: Office, clear!.
起居室,没问题
MAN 4: Living room, clear!.
全体撤离,六十秒
MAN 5: Everybody out. Sixty seconds.
[MOUTHING] 过来.
[MOUTHING] Come here.
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
她不在这里,她丈夫也不在
She's not here. No sign of the husband either.
你想过也许是那个俄国佬瞎掰吗?
WlNTER: Did it ever occur to you that that Russian was lying?
她为什么要跑?
PEABODY: Why'd she run? WlNTER: I don"t know.
不知,因为你要关她?
Because you were gonna lock her up?
从她的观点来
See it from her perspective.
也许她丈夫真的有危险
Maybe her husband is in some real danger.
也许,莎特并没有问题
Maybe, God forbid, Salt is who she says she is.
你的部门就负责猜
""Maybe"" is your department.
我得负责抓她找出真相
Mine is catching her so we can find out.
任务明确,不能活逮就处决
Protocol is clear. We bring her in or we bring her down.
你知道这女的是谁吗?
Do you have any idea who this woman is?
她为国奉献,对你毫无意义?
What she"s done for this country? Does that mean anything to you?.
应该要有吗?
Should it?
- 你妈在家吗? - 不在
Is your mom home? No.
- 不在?帮我一个忙吧? - 好
No?. Can you do me a favor? Yeah.
你能帮我照顾波特吗?
Hi. You baby-sit Burt for me?.
- 可以 - 可以?
Oh, yeah. Yeah?.
这里有钱可以买狗食
Here's some money for food.
波特
Hi, Burt.
你在写作业?
What you doing?. You doing homework?
对,数学
Yeah, math.
代数
Algebra.
我讨厌数学
I hate math.
高兴再见到你
MlKE: Hi. Nice to see you again.
你跟我说话?
You talking to me?
对,我之前在这里看过你
Yeah, I've seen you here before.
是啊,我常来这里
Yeah, l-- Yeah, I come here a lot.
你呢?
You?
我在这里工作在博物馆
Oh, l"m working here.At the museum.
我是节足动物学家
I'm an arachnologist.
什么?
A what?
我追踪蜘蛛
A spider hunter.
你就像一只蜘蛛
You look like one.
世界上有四万种蜘蛛
MlKE: There are 40,000 species of spiders in the world.
那只是我的
And that one is mine.
你发现的
You discovered it.
在北朝鲜境内
Inside North Korea.
我取名为彼得贝斯提
I named it Terrijoolsima peterbesti.
你懂吗?
Do you get that?
不懂,我该懂吗?
No. Should I?
彼得贝斯提是我以彼得贝斯特命的名
Peterbesti? I named it after Pete Best.
他是林哥之前的第一鼓手
The first drummer before Ringo.
贝斯特过去在甲壳虫乐队中从来就没有名气
Best never was a famous Beatle,
不过现在他是有名的蜘蛛了
but now he's a famous spider.
找到她了
I got her.
她往北跑向地铁车站
She's heading north towards the Metro station.
伊芙!
Ev!.
WlNTER: Ev!.
她往东走了,在购物广场里
She's eastbound, in the Penn Quarter Mall.
抱歉
Excuse me.
正赶往现场
MAN [OVER RADlO]: Will do. Headed there noW.
她在那里
There she is.
她往南方桥头走去,包围她
All teams, southbound toward the bridge. Box her in.
围住她
MAN 1 : Circle around!
莎特!别动!
Salt! Stop!.
紧盯着她
Coming up behind you!
在你后面
MAN 2: Keep her in your sights!.
该死!
Fuck!
退开!不要开枪!
Keep back!. Hold your fire!.
莎特!
Salt!
趴下!
Down!
莎特!
Salt!
散开
MAN 4: Spread out!
- 莎特! - 不要开枪!我是无辜的!
Salt! Don't shoot! Don't shoot, I'm innocent!
- 趴在地上 - 不要
On the ground. Now! Please don't. No!
趴下!莎特!趴在地上!
PEABODY: Down! Salt! Do it now! On the ground!
- 我要找我丈夫 - 你为什么要跑?
I have to find my husband.
我要找我丈夫
PEABODY: Why'd you run? To find my husband!
- 那不是理由 - 拜托,别开枪
PEABODY: That"s not a reason. SALT: Don't shoot.
- 退开! - 最后机会
Stay back!. PEABODY: Last chance.
我是无辜的,有人陷害我
I'm innocent. Somebody is setting me up!
- 别逼我对你开枪,莎特 - 把枪放下
Don't make me put you down. Put the gun down!
- 投降吧! - 拜托
PEABODY: Give yourself up! WlNTER: Come on, Ev.
照他说的做,我保证会查明事实
Do what he says. We'll sort this out, I promise.
我要逮捕你
I gotta bring you in,
结束了,脸朝下
Salt. It's over. Face down.
有人要暗杀俄国总统,你很清楚
Somebody's going to try to kill the Russian president.
快设法阻止!那才是你该担心的
Do something about that! That's what you should worry about.
你无处可跑了,投降吧
PEABODY: There's nowhere to run! Quit now!.
不,我什么都没做
No, I didn't do anything.
- 伊芙! - 不!
WlNTER: Get back! No!
她上了蓝色拖车,一号公路往北
She's on a blue semi. Route 1, heading north.
立刻设下路障
Get a roadblock in place now.
首府警方戒备中
WOMAN [OVER RADlO]: Metro Police on alert.
她在那里,在油罐车上
There she is. On the tanker.
停!停!
Stop. Stop!.
伊芙!
Ev!.
朋友,你的部门有内奸
You, my friend, have got a mole in your group.
这还不一定
We don't know that yet.
我认为她是训练有素的说谎高手
I'd say she's a trained goddamn liar
她说过的一切都是为了掩饰身份
and everything she's said has been to protect her cover.
你干脆说清楚你的感觉吧
Well, why don"t you tell me how you really feel about it?
走路肩、走路肩
Get up on the shoulder!. Get up on the shoulder!.
好,开下去
Okay, take it down.
该死!
Shit!
好吧
Okay.
泰德,我知道你是她朋友
Ted, I know you're her friend,
不过我们要在纽约布下天罗地网
but we gotta drop a net on New York.
就得立刻开始动手
We gotta do it now. MAN: Let's go!
通知负责俄国总统安全的特勤队
Notify the Secret Service on Matveyev's detail.
告诉他们,莎特可能会出现
Tell them Salt might be coming their way.
如果她要动手
And if she is,
奥洛夫也会在附近
Orlov may not be far behind either.
(伊芙在父母死亡车祸时受伤)
看过这个了?
PEABODY: You seen this?
莎特小时候在俄国待过一阵子
Salt spent time in Russia as a kid.
她和父母在88年发生车祸
She was in a car accident with her parents in '88.
父母都死了
They both died.
他们是美国大使馆聘用的老师
They were teachers at the U.S. Embassy for the American children of the staff.
所以我们一开始就让她去俄罗斯
That's why we put her on Russia in the first place.
我们今晚要搭上去纽约的飞机
We need to get on a plane to New York, tonight.
把奥洛夫的资料传给纽约警方
Send everything we've got on Orlov to N.Y.P.D.
在纽约市
MAN [ON RADlO]: And here in New York City,
安全警戒全面升高
security has been beefed up
准备工作将持续到深夜
and preparations are continuing well into the night
以迎接副总统麦威欧兹的告别式
for the funeral of Vice President MaxWell Oates.
预定明天抵达圣巴托罗缪教堂
Among the dignitaries attending the service at St.
参加此庄严仪式的高官显要中
BartholomeW's Church
有俄罗斯总统马特维耶夫
is Russian president Boris Matveyev,
已于今晚稍早抵达市中心
who arrived here in Manhattan earlier this evening.
由于地铁关闭,大众运输系统
Public transportation will experience delays,
将会有所延迟
with subway closures and...
伊芙
Evelyn.
看着我
Look at me.
如果有办法,我会杀了他们
If there was a way, I would kill them.
你不该来这里的
You shouldn't have come here.
这话什么意思?我不
What do you mean? I don't understand.
现在他们知道你了
Now they know who you are.
谁?
Who?.
伊芙
Evelyn.
谁?
Who?.
我愿意接受任何关于你的
I would accept anything about you,
不过要先让我知道才行
but I need to know.
我, 我
So look at me. Look at me.
告诉我,好吗?
Just tell me, okay?
告诉我
Just tell me.
我的工作
I work...
我是中情局的人
I work for the ClA.
现在你明白了
So you see, there's...
我们不会有未来
There's no future for us.
你跟我在一起不安全
You're not safe with me.
我不想要安全
I don't wanna be safe.
我认识你
I know you,
我想跟你在一起
and I wanna be with you.
我想和你厮守一生
I want to spend the rest of my life with you.
好吗?
Okay?.
好
Okay.
欢迎来到纽约,贺小姐
Welcome to New York, Miss Hernandez.
豪华套房住宿一晚
One night, a deluxe room.
贺小姐,需要帮忙提行李吗?
Do you need any help with your luggage?.
不用,我自己来
Nope, I got it. Thanks.
我把这些放进衣橱里吧?
WOMAN: I'll put these in the closet, sir?.
好
MAN: Yeah, fine.
(圣巴托罗缪街口)
(地铁系统
隧道出入口)
(通风口)
(教堂隧道)
我郑重宣示...
WlNTER: I do solemnly swear
I do solemnly swear
我将支持并捍卫美国宪法...
that I will support and defend the Constitution of the United States
对抗所有国内外敌人...
WlNTER: against all enemies, foreign and domestic.
against all enemies, foreign and domestic.
我将忠实履行...
WlNTER: That I will faithfully discharge
That I will faithfully discharge
我即将就职的责任...
WlNTER: the duties of the office on which I'm about to enter.
GROUP: the duties of the office on which I am about to enter.
- 请帮助我上帝 - 请帮助我上帝
WlNTER: So help me God. GROUP: So help me God.
今天的纽约很庄严
WOMAN: A solemn day here in New York City.
欧兹副总统的告别式
The funeral of Vice President Maxwell Oates,
五任参议员兼冷战斗士
a former five-term U.S. senator and Cold War warrior
他最伟大的遗产可能是创造出
whose greatest legacy may be as architect
美俄关系的新纪元
of the new era of Russian-American relations.
俄罗斯总统马特维耶夫
Russian president Boris Matveyev
自莫斯科来此担任名誉扶棺人
has journeyed from Moscow to be an honorary pallbearer
向他西方世界最伟大的朋友致意
to the man he's called his greatest friend in the West.
戒备范围多大?
What's the security perimeter?
两层人墙,整个街区都在控制中
We're two deep inside and we own this entire block.
这些还是特勤人员,不是中情局的
And those are Secret Service agents, not ClA.
放心拉
So relax.
真有趣
That's real funny.
我不知道你们还会开玩笑
Didn"t know you guys told jokes.
全体,立定
MAN: Detail, halt.
向前,走
Forward, march.
由于告别式,51街地铁站关闭
MAN [OVER SPEAKER]: Due to the funeral, the 51 st Street station is closed.
Repeat: Due to the funeral, the 51 st Street station is closed.
怎么回事?
MAN : What--? Hey, what's going on?
有烟
Hey!. There's smoke.
退后,大家让开
POLlCE OFFICER: Step back, step back. Everybody, move out of the way.
伊莲诺,看到你真好
Eleanor. Good to see you.
谢谢
Thank you.
波里斯
Boris.
总统先生
Mr. President.
你好
Hello.
请坐下
PIease be seated.
静候总统致词
WOMAN [OVER RADlO]: Stand by for president's speech.
巡视教堂周边
MAN: Patrolling church exterior.
侧门不准任何人进出
No one in or out the side doors.
欧兹先生
Mrs. Oates.
伊莲诺、乔、玛丽莎、唐诺
Eleanor, Joe, Marissa, Donald...
总统讲完后,唱诗班唱歌
After the president, the choir sings,
然后马特维耶夫宣讲颂辞
then Matveyev delivers the eulogy.
要是你手下敢作乱
If your girl tries anything here,
那一定要惊天动地
it'd have to be pretty amazing.
我早知他的贡献绝对超群绝伦
LEWlS: I knew he would bring more to the job than just his years of experience.
身为副总统
As vice president,
他让全世界看到美国人的典范
he showed the world the best of what it is to be an American.
而今天
And today,
世界向一位伟人道别
the world says goodbye to a great man.
我去检查后面
I'll check the back.
LZ4 ,没问题
Lima Zulu 4, clear.
我与欧兹副总统的友谊
My friendship with Maxwell Oates
开启于最不可能的地方
began in the unlikeliest of places:
LZ4 ,请说
WOMAN [OVER RADlO]: Lima Zulu 4, come in.
在谈判桌上
MATVEYEV: Across the negotiating table...
回报状况,LZ4
WOMAN : What's your status, Lima Zulu 4?
两员失联
We got two M lAs.
LZ4在地窑入口外侧隧道
Lima Zulu 4 in the utility tunnel outside
还有LZ5
the crypt entrance and Lima Zulu 5.
我去地窖
I'm heading down to the crypt.
下面出了状况
Some kind of trouble down there.
怎么回事?快回答
What's going on, guys?. Talk to me.
LZ1、23在地窖会合,重复
Subunits Lima Zulu 1, 2 and 3, converge on the crypt. Repeat:
在地窖会合
Converge on the crypt.
他成就非凡
He made all the difference, and for that,
因此他获得我的尊崇与景仰
he will always have my respect and admiration.
那也是我朋友欧兹会说的
That is what my friend Maxwell Oates would have said.
老天
WOMAN: What's going on?
马特维耶夫
Matveyev.
去救马特维耶夫
Get goddamn Matveyev.
叫炸弹小组来
MAN 1 : Get the bomb squad in here!
快!快!
MAN 2: Go, go!.
放下!
Drop it!
这里有医护人员吗?
MAN 1 : Any MTs down here?
我看到她了
MAN 2: I see her.
把手举起来
MAN 3: Keep your hands up!.
枪手在12点方向
Shooter's at 1 2 o'clock.
枪!她有枪!
Gun! She's got a gun. She has a gun!
别动!
MAN 4: Don't move!
- 不准动! - 手举高
Do not move! Do not move!. MAN 5: Keep your hands up!.
逮捕她
MAN 6: Take her down, take her down!.
检查其它武器
MAN 7: Check for other weapons.
立刻派医疗小组来地窖
We need a medical crew in the crypt immediately.
我摸不到脉搏
I can"t feel a pulse.
管辖权很明确这是纽约市
Jurisdiction is clear. This is New York City.
纽约警局逮到她她就会被送到第一分局
N.Y.P.D. has her. She's going to 1 Police Plaza.
- 我不是要争论管辖权 - 我们还不清楚,长官
I'm not arguing jurisdiction. We don't know yet, sir.
- 枪击者是中情局的人,我认识她 - 是,我会到的
The shooter is ClA. I know her. Yes, I'll be there.
我会搭下一台直升机去
I'll be on the next chopper out.
- 叫你的长官打给市长 - 让开...各位
Have your superior call the mayor. MAN: Open up, guy, open up.
让开
[SIREN WAILlNG]
退后
Back it up! Back it up!.
继续走、继续走
Come on, guys. Keep moving. Keep moving. Keep moving.
快走、快走
Let's go, let's go.
小心这家伙
Hey, watch this guy, watch this guy.
- 退开! - 继续走
MAN 1 : Back up!. MAN 2: Keep moving.
退开!
MAN 1 : Sir, back up!.
为什么?
Why?
Why?!.
你知道你手上染了多少血吗?
Do you have any idea how much blood is on your hands?
你等着死在黑牢里吧
You're gonna rot in a hole, Salt.
我会亲自确认这件事,最黑的黑牢
I'm gonna see to it personally! A dark hole!
你控制一下
PEABODY: Get ahold of yourself.
开门、开门
Get the door, get the door.
- 放开我 - 退开!退开!
Get off me!. Back off, man! Back off!
好了,走吧
That's it. Let's go.
关门!快、快!
Close it! Go, go, go!
马特维耶夫在送医途中宣告死亡
Matveyev was declared dead en route to the hospital.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
还好
WlNTER: Yeah.
你没错看她
You were right about her.
她有机会杀我
She had the drop on me, Ted.
她为什么不开枪?
Why didn't she shoot?
娜塔莎
SHNAlDER: Natasha.
Natasha.
是你吗?
Is that you?
他们给你一个新面孔吗?
Did they give you a new face?
我明天要回家了,史奈德
I'm going home tomorrow, Shnaider.
格洛斯尼的家?
Home to Grozny?.
我的家在宾州?瑞斯堡
My home is in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania.
我最喜欢的地方是在佛恩街的麦当劳
My favorite place there is McDonald's on Fern Street
因为离河很近
because it's near the river.
但是我再也不想去了
But I won't want to go there anymore
因为我的父母已经死了
because my mother and father are dead.
娜塔莎
SHNAlDER: Natasha,
你会想念我吗?
will you miss me?.
我就叫伊芙莎特
My name is Evelyn Salt.
员警受伤!注意!
Cop down, cop down! Hear me!
下车,把手放头上
MAN 1 : Get out of the car with your hands on your head!.
快点!
MAN 2: Right now!
手举起来!
Hands in the air!
你看到没?
MAN 1 : Hey, did you see that?
快叫那些人来帮忙
MAN 2: Hey, get those guys over here.
叫他们来帮忙
Get them over here to help.
快来帮我把他弄出来,快帮忙
Somebody help me get him out. Help me get him out.
你要念哪一家学校?
What college will you attend?
普林斯顿大学
YOUNG SALT: Princeton University.
你要去哪里工作?
Where will you work?
中央情报局
YOUNG SALT: The Central lntelligence Agency.
你要信任谁?
Who will you trust?.
谁都不信
No one.
要有耐心
Be very patient.
要记得你的训练
Remember your training.
要记得你并不是唯一的一个
Remember, you're not the only one.
还有很多人
There are many others.
你们全都在等待出击
All of you waiting to strike.
- 是的 - 我们会出击
Yes. And we will strike.
一起联手
Together.
对
Yes.
等等
Wait.
有一天,我会去找你们
One day, I will come for all of you.
你好,伊芙
MAN: Hello, Evelyn.
我是美国大使馆的科伦萧
I'm Martin Crenshaw from the U.S. Embassy.
对于你们的意外我们很遗憾
We're very sorry about your family's accident.
美国大使馆外的暴民
WOMAN [ON TV]: Rioters outside the U.S.
声援他们新领袖的发言
Embassy cheered their neW leader's words
并要求他采取强烈行动
and called on him to take strong action against What they are calling
反击一桩由美国主导的恐怖行动
a state-sponsored act of terrorism on the part of the U. S.
这些暴民在俄罗斯各地
These riots are sparking similar outbreaks
激起类似的反美游行
of anti-American protests across Russia.
新任俄罗斯总统说"我们要复仇"
MAN [ON TV] : "We will strike back, '" says the new Russian president,
愤怒指责在今天由美国情报员
angrily condemning today's assassination
伊芙莎特所主导的暗杀行动
by American intelligence officer Evelyn Salt.
纵使马特维耶夫总统的遗体
As the body of slain President Matveyev
正在运往莫斯科的途中
is on its Way back to Moscow,
俄罗斯各地仍爆发反美暴动
anti-American riots have erupted across Russia,
美国外交官车辆在莫斯科遇袭
with bombings of U. S. diplomats' cars in Moscow.
俄罗斯武装部队进入高度警戒
The Russian armed forces have been put on high alert.
为因应急速扩大的危机
Responding to a rapidly escalating crisis,
路易斯总统召集紧急白宫会议
President Lewis has called for an emergency White House meeting
内阁、军方领袖与北约代表均出席
with cabinet members, military leaders and NA TO representatives.
你好,宣科夫同志
[I N RUSSlAN] Greetings, Comrade Chenkov!.
你好,奥洛夫同志
[SPEAKS IN RUSSlAN]
我在华盛顿看到你时,差点失控
When I saw you in Washington, I almost ran to you.
你不该结婚的
[IN ENGLlSH] You were not supposed to get married.
除非结婚能带来策略性的优点
Not unless it had great tactical advantage.
我结婚是为了看起来正常
I did it to seem normal.
你今天逃走时,我心想
ORLOV: When you escaped today, I thought:
就连我也没想到你有这么行
""Even I could not have hoped for so much.""
你是我最神的创作
You are my greatest creation.
是你把我训练的好
You trained me well.
我丈夫
My husband,
在你手里?
you have him?
我必须要确认
I had to be certain.
现在你信任我了?
But now you trust me?.
完全信任
Completely.
那么
SALT: So tell me
接下来要做什么
what's next.
接下来,第二阶段
ORLOV: Next, part two:
控制这国家的核子武器
We seize control of this country's atomic weapons.
怎么做?
How?
你会知道的
[IN RUSSlAN] You'll see.
好
[IN RUSSlAN] All right.
你准备好看着他死吗?
Are you ready to watch him die?
给我枪
Give me the gun.
那样就太容易了
That would be too easy.
放水
满意了?
[IN RUSSlAN] Satisfied?.
我很满意
[IN RUSSlAN] I'm satisfied.
同志们
Comrades,
我们的姐妹回来了
our sister has rejoined us.
俄罗斯将浴火重生
Russia will rise from the ashes
从熊熊战火中冉冉升起
of the greatest war the world has ever seen.
全世界将会注视我们
And the world will hear us!
注视
ALL [lN RUSSIAN]: Will hear.
欢迎回到我们的大家庭,姐妹
Welcome back to our family, sister.
姐妹
Sister.
俄罗斯已然改变
Russia has changed.
不过我们的生命将不会白费
But our lives will not be wasted.
你要去见一位特务身着北约制服,在一架飞机上
You're to meet an agent, NATO uniform, at a plane here.
机身编码是N182SL
Tail number N1 82SL.
他会给你最终的指示
Final instructions will come from him.
就这样
That's it.
在这之后,我们停止联系
After this, we go dark.
中止一切联络
Radio silent.
我将不会再与你联络
[IN ENGLlSH] You won't hear from me again,
我的女儿
my daughter.
厮守终身
MlKE: Forever and ever.
奥洛夫跟你谈过了
SHNAlDER [lN RUSSIAN]: Have you heard from Orlov?
有,他最后只说"行动"
MAN [lN RUSSlAN]: Yes. Last word was ""go."'
宣科夫
[IN ENGLlSH] Chenkov.
你记得我吗?
Do you remember me?
宣科夫
BOY: Chenkov.
你有想过我吗?
Did you miss me?
史奈德?
Shnaider?.
你来这里多久了?
How long have you been here?
我在你之后一年离开俄国
I left Russia one year after you.
到了布拉格
To Prague.
我担任北约对白宫联络官三年了
I've been the NATO liaison to the White House for three years.
艾德、华托马斯上校
Colonel Edward Tomas.
你是我的随员
And you are my attache.
你的证件
Your lD.
不用担心,我们有的是时间
Don't worry, we have plenty of time.
更重要的是
More importantly,
我们的任务
our mission.
地下碉堡
The bunker e
就在白宫地下第八层
ight stories below the White House.
那就是总统要去的地方
That's where the president needs to be.
要怎么做?
How do we do it?.
他会去的,那是我的任务
Don't worry, he'll be there.
我要确保他会去
That's my job. I'll make sure he's there.
那我的任务呢?
What's my job?
宣科夫,你记得吗?
Do you remember, Chenkov,
我们还年轻时
when we were young
你每一件事都要拿第一名
and you had to finish first in everything?.
每件事都要做到最好
Had to be the best at everything.
就算被揍,你也要抢第一
Though you knew you would be beaten with a cane, you had to finish first.
我记得
I remember.
今晚,你又会抢在我前面了
Tonight you will finish ahead of me again.
今晚,你要毙掉美国总统
Tonight you will kill America's president.
证件
IDs, please.
打开引擎盖和后车厢
Pop the hood and open the trunk.
我检查旁边
MAN 1 : I'll check the side.
(托马斯上校、维克少校)
中心,我是海斯
HAYES: Control, this is Hayes.
这里有托马斯上校和维克少校
I have a Colonel Tomas and a Major Vicek.
底盘没问题
MAN 2: Undercarriage is clean.
后面没问题
MAN 1 : Back's clean.
上校、少校
Colonel. Major.
没问题了
All clear.
你很清楚程序,上校
WOMAN: You know the drill, colonel.
炮弹碎片,塞尔维亚的地雷
Shrapnel. A Serbian landmine.
他们找的比医生还仔细
They've spent more time looking at it than the doctor did.
请走过来
Step through, please, sir.
转身
Turn around.
谢谢
Thank you.
走过来,伸手
Step through. Arms out.
耐心是关键
Patience is key.
我来这两年了,其他人待了更久
I've been coming here for two years, others have been here longer.
其他人是谁?
What others?.
我不知道
I don't know.
不过你是最行的,我是最差的
But you were the best of us and I was the least.
这里一定还有其他人来完成大业
There must be others, here to finish what we begin.
托马斯上校,很高兴再见到你
Colonel Tomas. Good to see you again.
- 维克少校 - 幸会
Major Vicek. PIeasure.
你们有两分钟检查北约的观点
You'll have minutes to preview NATO's point of view before the meeting.
泰德,你的探员莎特
Now, Ted, your Russian Cl agent, Salt.
对于她,你有什么情报?
What can you tell us about her?.
我们认为她可能是俄罗斯密探
We think she may be a Soviet plant,
数年前被安插进来
inserted years ago in preparation
为KGB的某个"毁灭日"做准备
for something the KGB called Day X.
那一天,要开启大规模攻击
A day marking the start of a large strike against
对付美国与其盟邦
the U.S. and her allies.
这应该是总统了
This should be the president now.
你有个艰巨的任务,宣科夫
You have a big job, Chenkov,
不过你行的
but you can do it.
你还没告诉我,你的任务是什么
You still haven't told me what your job is.
家
Home.
我要回家
I'm going home.
趴下!找掩护!
MAN 1 : Down!. Take cover!
保护总统
MAN 2: Get the president!
她有枪，退后！
WOMAN: A gun! He"s got a gun! MAN 3: Get back!
退后!
Get back!
- 你没事吧 - 没事
Are you okay, sir? Yes.
- 该死 - 依照程序,酋长前往地下碉堡
Goddamn it. Geronimo is SOP, downward mobile.
救命!这里!
MAN: Help, over here!.
快叫医护人员
Get a medic! Get a medic!
我想我看到她了
I think I saw her.
你看到谁?
You saw who?
莎特
Salt.
我想我在走廊上看到她了
I think I saw her in the corridor.
另一位北约军官
The other NATO officer.
她在这里
She's here.
确认
Check.
- 安全 - 走
Clear. Move.
快!
Go!.
我们看见第二位攻击者伊芙
We may have a visual on a second assailant. Evelyn Salt.
重复:伊芙莎特在警戒区内
Repeat: Evelyn Salt on premises.
一身北约军官打扮
May be dressed as a NATO officer.
这不是演习
MAN [OVER SPEAKER]: This is not a drill.
白宫正遭受攻击
The White House is under attack.
请前往最近出口
If you are near an exit,
立刻依序离开
please proceed outside in an orderly manner.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
我要确保这条走廊安全无虞
I need this hallway cleared to the left, now!
中心,请求启动地下碉堡
Command, this is Jenks. I need the PEOC bunker up and running.
这若是俄罗斯政府授权的行动
If this was authorized by the Russian government,
这就是战争行为,我们会复仇
it is an act of war, and we will respond.
请前往最近出口
If you are near an exit,
立刻依序离开
please proceed outside in an orderly manner.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
- 安全! - 走吧,长官
MAN 1 : Clear! Let's go, sir.
A小队,行动
MAN 2: Alpha team!
快、快
Move, move.
关上
Close it.
立刻依序离开
Please proceed outside in an orderly manner.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
快、快
Go, go.
酋长五秒内抵达碉堡门口
Geronimo approaching bunker door in five seconds.
安全
Clear.
她会跟来吗?
WlNTER: Any chance she could follow?.
门一关上,连我的人都进不来
My own men couldn't get through that door.
是啊,可惜她不是你的人
Yeah, well, unfortunately, she isn't one of yours.
好了,走
MAN: Okay, go.
等门关好再走
Stay until it"s shut and sealed.
酋长安全
Geronimo secured.
帮我接梅孚局长
LEWlS: Get me Director Medford.
是,长官
WOMAN: Yes, sir.
我想我们该严重考虑
WlNTER: Sir, I think we need to seriously consider the possibility
今天,现在,就是毁灭日的开始
that today, right now, could be the start of Day X.
总统先生,局长上线了
Mr. President, Director Medford is up.
局长,情况如何?
Marion, what's the situation?
资料应该正显示在您的屏幕上
It should be coming up on one of your screens.
这里显示西伯利亚的移动飞弹
What you see there represents temperature drops
温度下降
in mobile missile units in Siberia.
这表示俄罗斯正在部署飞弹
It means the Russians are deploying their missiles to the field.
地面人员己确认此事,总统先生
And that's been confirmed on the ground, Mr. President.
我强烈建议提升战备到二级状态
M r. President, I strongly recommend we go from DEFCON 4 to DEFCON 2.
至少在前线是如此
At least at our forward bases.
就这么办
Do it.
由于俄罗斯已部署飞弹
And since the Russians have deployed,
我们要考虑核武器攻击的可能
we need to look at our own nuclear attack options.
不认真考虑,就无法遏阻他们
It's not on the table, it's not a deterrent.
谢了,局长,我们会再联络你
Thanks, Marion. We'll come back to you.
长官
Sir.
外门卡住了,没有反应
The outer portal door is jammed. No response.
大部分的监视器也失灵了
And we just lost the feed from most of our security cameras.
我们看不见,不过没人能进来
We're blind down here and no one can enter this facility.
中心,视讯无法传输
Command, our eyes are down.
地下碉堡安全外门也故障
We have a PEOC outer security door malfunction.
快点离开
Get out there now.
封住这个房间
Seal this room.
那条走廊,确认清楚
Down that corridor. Secure it.
受害者被送往华盛顿医院
Victims are being taken to George Washington Hospital.
据报白宫也有伤亡
Reports are coming in that there are casualties at the White House.
我是霍华路易斯总统
This is President Howard Lewis.
进行认证
Proceed with authentication.
是,总统先生
Y es, Mr. President.
- 准备开始认证
MAN : Ready to commence authentication.
- Z…
Zulu.
- T - F…
T ango. Echo.
- 7 - 9…
Seven. LEWlS: Niner.
- J - X…
Juliett. LEWlS: X-ray.
- S - 7…
AlDE: Sierra. LEWlS: Seven.
- A - N…
AlDE: Alfa. LEWlS: Mike.
- C - W…
AlDE: Charlie. LEWlS: Whiskey.
- 5 - 6…
AlDE: Five. LEWlS: Six.
T…
AlDE: Tango.
认证密码确认
MAN: Authentication codes confirmed.
一切交给你了,总统先生
It's all yours now, Mr. President.
上帝与你同在
God be with you.
攻击选项和目标由您控制
Attack options and targeting under your control, Mr. President.
安德斯、纳布洛,你们在哪?
Anders and Nablo, what's your location?
[OVER RADlO] Anders and Nablo, what"s your location?
门外的监视器还能用吗?接上来
Is the camera outside this door working? Put it up.
戴尔探员,报告情况
Officer Dryer, what"s your status?.
戴尔探员,请说话
Officer Dryer, come in.
联邦通讯委员会
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKER]: Federal Communication Commission
启动紧急警报系统
is activating the Emergency Alert System.
那是什么?
WOMAN : Who the hell's that?.
是她
That's her.
是伊芙莎特
That's Evelyn Salt.
她来了，进入一级戒备状态
MAN : She's in. Go to DEFCON 1.
把你的枪给我,我会用枪
Give me your side arm.
不,总统身边只有特勤人员能持枪
No, sir. Only Secret Service possess firearms in the president's vicinity.
去它的规定,外面有敌人的特务
Screw protocol. We got an enemy agent.
规定就是规定
Protocol is protocol, sir.
死人就是死人
And dead is dead.
躲我后面
Behind me!.
我是国家安全顾问
I'm the national security advisor.
已经不是了
WlNTER: Not anymore.
坐下
Sit down.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我的名字叫尼可莱塔寇夫斯基
My name, Mr. President, is Nikolai Tarkovsky.
照我说的去做
And unless you do exactly as I say,
否则我就是你最后看到的人
I will be the last person you will ever see.
我们一起挑选攻击目标吧?
Shall we look at some selective attack options?
你去死吧
Go to hell.
攻击选项准备就绪
RECORDED VOlCE: Selective attack options ready.
泰德?
SALT: Ted?.
紧急行动讯息...
Emergency action message released by...
恭喜,宣科夫同志,你成功了
[IN RUSSlAN] Congratulations, Comrade Chenkov. You made it.
你怎么不告诉我?
SALT: Why didn't you tell me?
我试过很多次,不过
I tried many times, but...
我的孤独是我唯一的朋友
My loneliness was my only friend.
你没跟我们一起,我不会忘记你的
You weren't with us in Russia. I would have remembered you.
我比你早一期
I was a class ahead, comrade.
奥洛夫摩下最闪亮的星星
The brightest of any of Orlov's stars.
现在我很荣幸能发动攻击
And now it's my honor to launch the attack.
抱歉
Excuse me.
选择攻击目标
Selective attack targets acquired.
德黑兰
Tehran.
麦加
Mecca.
麦加?
Mecca?
德黑兰?
T ehran?
我们计划的第二步
Part two of our plan.
杀死九百万人
Kill nine million people.
激怒十亿穆斯林教徒
Enrage a billion Muslims.
美国会死的很难
America will suffer a painful death.
行动许可连结
Permissive action links initiated.
(授权)
启动
飞弹准备中
Missiles arming.
核武指挥权
Nuclear command
移交空中
posts airborne.
让我加入你吧
[IN RUSSlAN] Let me join you.
洲际弹道飞弹设定
ICMs set to
最大破坏能量
maximum yield.
你刚来到中情局时
[I N ENGLlSH] You know, when you first came to Langley,
我没想到我能守住秘密
I didn't think l"d be able to do it.
我没想到能够
I didn't think I'd be able to
抗拒吐露身份的诱惑
resist the temptation to say something.
后来你认识了麦克
Then you met Mike and,
结果情况改变了
well, things changed.
让我加入你
Let me join you.
这些年来就在我眼前
All these years right in front of me
而我却完全不知道
and I never knew.
让我加入你
Let me join you.
我想跟你一起
I want to be with you.
(俄罗斯总统没死!)
众人都认为已死的人
MAN [ON TV]: The man we thought Was dead has
奇迹似地复活了
made a resurrection that is miraculous.
马特维耶夫总统还活着
President Matveyev is alive.
您所看到的是俄罗斯现场传回
We 're going to Russia. What you are seeing
俄罗斯总统飞抵莫斯科
are live pictures of Russian president Matveyev
近郊机场的现场画面
arriving at the airport outside of MoscoW.
这太惊人了
This is astonishing.
据医生说,总统死亡的乌龙
According to his doctors, President Matveyev's mistaken death
是由蜘蛛毒液萃取出的毒素
is attributed to a temporary paralysis
所引发的暂时性麻痹
from a toxin derived from spider venom.
对于那些可能不会跟踪当天事件的人...
A recap for those Who may not have been following the events of the day...
至少我没弄错
At least I was rig ht.
我当时就觉得在北朝鲜已经失去你了
I had a feeli ng we'd lost you back there in North Korea.
我看得出麦克英勇的王子行动
I could see how moved you were by Mike"s
让你有多感动
little white-knight routine.
你应该要招募他
You were supposed to recruit him, Ev,
不是爱上他
not fall in love with him.
所以我叫奥洛夫去逮他
That's why I told Orlov to pick him up.
对了,麦克好吗?
By the way, how is Mike?.
奥洛夫死了
[IN ENGLlSH] Orlov is dead.
那真是好消息
Well, that"s good news.
省了我的麻烦
Saved me the trouble.
我得真的扭断他的手
I had to practically twist his arm
才能逼他去中情局揭穿你的身份
to get him to blow your cover at the ClA.
他希望事情结束后,你能活命
You see, he wanted you to come out of this thing alive.
不过你需要有人垫背
But you needed somebody to take the blame.
我是替死鬼
I'm the patsy.
而我是英雄
And l"m the hero.
恭喜了,伊芙
Congratulations, Ev.
你即将红遍天下
You're about to become famous.
(重新确认身份)
请求确认身份
Identity confirmation requested.
身份已确认
Identity confirmed.
义勇兵三型飞弹电力满载
Minuteman lll lCBMs' batteries up to poWer.
授权99%
Authorization, 9 percent.
快!
Go!.
行动许可连结
Permissive action links
授权
initiated.
核子潜舰待命
Trident submarines at firing readiness.
请求许可发射
Permission to launch.
趴下,快!
Get down on the floor, now!
我叫你趴下!
I said now!.
发射程序解除,系统回收
Launch sequence aborted. Systems restored.
- 快、快、快 - 把手举起来
MAN 1 : Move, move, move! MAN 2: Show me your hands!
要他们趴
MAN 3: Get down!
- 手举起来 - 你是谁?
MAN 4: What is your name, sir?
我是中情局的温特,快救总统
I'm Theodore Winter, ClA. Help the president.
总统先生
MAN 5: Mr. President.
总统先生,你听得见吗?
Mr. President, can you hear me?
- 别动 - 急救小组马上到
MAN 6: Hold still. MAN 7: EMT's on the way.
送尸袋来,至少有七人死亡
MAN 8: Make sure they got body bags. At least seven.
她穿着防弹背心
MAN 9: She's wearing a vest.
五分钟后会议室见,我要清理一下
WlNTER: I'll meet you in five minutes. I wanna get cleaned up.
我要她单独关一间房
And I want her alone in a room.
我要她供出其他的俄国密探
If there are other KAs out there, I want her talking.
她不会说的
She won't talk.
她受过训练,无论如何都不会说
She's trained not to, no matter what we do to her.
我们要找这些人,就得自己找
If we're gonna find these people, we gotta do it.
有人已经动手,至少清了一部分
Somebody already did. At least some of them.
东河船上,12名死者,包括奥洛夫
Barge on the East River. Twelve dead, including Orlov.
是谁干的?
Who did that?
不知,鉴识小组正在调查
Don't know. Forensics are on it.
我去整理一下,我马上回来
I'm gonna get cleaned up. I'll be right back.
你受伤了,坐下来吧?
Well, sir, you're injured. Why don't you have a seat?
我们会照顾你
We'll take a look at you.
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
伤口很深
Pretty good gash there.
来里面有玻璃
Looks like you got a piece of glass in there.
她又杀人了
MAN [OVER EARPlECE]: She killed someone else.
是泰德温特,你最好快上来
It's Winter. It's Ted Winter, sir. You better get up here.
他、快看看他
MAN 1 : Check him. Check him!.
检查生命迹象
MAN 2: Checking vitals.
我摸不到脉搏
I'm not getting a pulse. I'm not getting much.
坐下
Sit down.
飞行的15分钟内,她是你的
She's yours for 1 5 minutes during the flight.
- 把手给我 - 之后就是联邦调查局的
PEABODY: Give me your hands. MAN: Then she's the FBl's.
嘿.
Hey.
为什么要杀他?
Why'd you kill him?.
因为一定要有人动手
Because somebody had to.
什么?
What?.!.
我猜你认为人人都表里如一
By this, I take it you think everybody is who they say they are.
你在奥洛夫投诚时就觉得有问题
You knew something was wrong the moment Orlov walked in.
我也是
So did l.
我们只是不知道是什么
We just didn't know what it was.
温特知道
Winter did.
温特
Winter?
你要我相信是温特要发射飞弹?
You expect me to believe that Winter was gonna launch the missiles
而你拯救了全世界?
and you saved the world?
我要你相信,对
I would like you to believe that, yeah.
这是很大的指控
That's a big accusation.
反正
Well,
他死了,死无对证
he"s dead now so he can"t defend himself.
我想你必须自己决定
I guess you'll just have to decide for yourself.
有多少像你一样的人?
How many more like you are there?
像我?
Like me?
没有
None.
像他的?
Like him?.
多到你我都无法对付
More than you or I can handle alone.
你真以为训练精良的俄国密探
You really think a trained Soviet agent
无法近距离枪杀俄罗斯总统?
couldn't kill the Russian president at point-blank range if she wanted to?
或是无法杀你?
Or you, for that matter.
告别式那天我可以杀你却没动手
I could've killed you at the funeral and I didn't.
你投降是因为我让你别无选择
You surrendered to me because I gave you no choice.
你很清楚
You know better.
我有选择
I had a choice.
你很清楚
You know better.
(奥洛夫死亡现场发现绍特指纹)
要是我相信你
If I did believe you,
我不是说我信你,只是就算我信
and I'm not saying for a second that I do, but if I did,
别人也不会信
nobody else would.
也许你可以换个角度想
Well, maybe you can think of a way around that.
他们夺走了我的一切
They took everything from me.
我要宰了他们
I'll kill them.
预计到达时间，四分钟后.
ETA, four minutes.
瞎扯!
Bullshit!
我们正飞往波托马克河西南方
PlLOT: We are approaching the Potomac, heading due south and west.
宰了他们!
Go get them.
莎特!
Salt!
绕回去!
Circle back! Circle back!
新上任的美国总统乔瑟夫史戴本今天宣布
NEWSCASTER: New U.S. President Joseph Steppens announced today
由于娜塔莎宣科夫
that with the death of Natasha Chenkov,
也就是在美国名为伊芙莎特的死所有的恐怖分子集团成员
known in the U. S. as Evelyn Salt, all elements of the terrorist group
都已经被歼灭这是在他...
have been eliminated. The announcement came
维和访问莫斯科时宣布的
during his Moscow peacekeeping visit
而在访问俄罗斯途中史戴本总统对...
where President Steppens paused to lay floWers
在1974年空难死亡的父母和姐妹的陵墓...
at the site of the 1 974 plane crash that killed his parents and sister
献花致意
while on a tour of Russia.
片尾之后请看第二结局版
俄罗斯已然改变
Russia has changed.
不过我们的生命将不会白费
But our lives will not be wasted.
你要去见一位特务   身着北约制服，在一架飞机上
You're to meet an agent,NATO uniform, at a plane here.
机身编码是N182SL
Tail number N182SL.
他会给你最终的指示
Final instructions will come from him.
-就这样 -就这样
- That's it. - That's it.
在这之后，我们停止联系
After this, we go dark.
中止一切联络
Radio silent.
我将不会再与你联络
You won't hear from me again...
我的女儿
...my daughter.
奥洛夫跟你谈过了
Have you heard from Orlov?
有，他最后只说〝行动〞
Yes. Last word was "go."
宣科夫
Chenkov.
你记得我吗？
Do you remember me?
宣科夫
Chenk ov.
你有想过我吗？
Did you miss me?
史奈德？
Shnaider?
你来这里多久了？
How long have you been here?
我在你之后一年离开俄国
I left Russia one year after you.
到了布拉格
To Prague.
我担任北约对白宫联络官三年了
I've been the NATO liaison to the White House for three years.
艾德华汤玛仕上校
Colonel Edward Tomas.
你是我的随员
And you are my attach?
你的证件
Your ID.
不用担心，我们有的是时间
Don't worry, we have plenty of time.
更重要的是  我们的任务
More importantly, our mission.
地下碉堡就在白宫地下第八层
The bunker eight storeys below the White House.
那就是总统要去的地方
That's where the president needs to be.
要怎么做？
How do we do it?
他会去的，那是我的任务
Don't worry, he'll be there. That's my job.
我要确保他会去
I'll make sure he's there.
那我的任务呢？
- What's my job?
宣科夫，你记得吗？
- Do you remember, Chenkov...
我们还年轻时
...when we were young and you
你每一件事都要拿第一名
had to finish first in everything?
每件事都要做到最好
Had to be the best at everything.
就算被揍，你也要抢第一
Though you knew you would be beaten with a cane, you had to finish first.
我记得
I remember.
今晚，你又会抢在我前面了
Tonight you will finish ahead of me again.
今晚，你要毙掉美国总统
Tonight you will kill America's president.
证件
IDs, please.
打开引擎盖和后车厢
Pop the hood and open the trunk.
我检查旁边
I'll check the side.
(托马斯上校、维克少校)
中心，我是海斯  这里有汤玛仕上校和维克少校
Control, this is Hayes.I have a Colonel Tomas and a Major Vicek.
底盘没问题
Undercarriage is clean.
后面没问题
Back's clean.
上校、少校
没问题了
Colonel. Major. All clear.
你很清楚程序，上校
You know the drill, colonel.
炮弹碎片，塞尔维亚的地雷
Shrapnel. A Serbian landmine.
他们找的比医生还仔细
They've spent more time looking at it than the doctor did.
请走过来
Step through, please, sir.
转身
Turn around.
谢谢
Thank you.
走过来，伸手
- Step through. Arms out.
耐心是关键
- Patience is key.
我来这两年了，其他人待了更久
I've been coming here for two years,others have been here longer.
-其他人是谁？ -我不知道
- What others? - I don't know.
不过你是最行的，我是最差的
But you were the best of us and I was the least.
这里一定还有其他人来完成大业
There must be others,here to finish what we begin.
汤玛仕上校，很高兴再见到你
Colonel Tomas.Good to see you again.
-维克少校  -幸会
- Major Vicek.- Pleasure.
你们有两分钟检查北约的观点
You'll have minutes to preview NATO's point of view before the meeting.
泰德，你的探员莎特
Now, Ted, your Russian CI agent, Salt.
对于她，你有什么情报？
- What can you tell us about her?
我们认为她可能是俄罗斯密探
- We think she may be a Soviet plant...
数年前被安插进来
...inserted years ago in preparation
为KGB的某个〝毁灭日〞做准备
for something the KGB called Day X.
那一天，要开启大规模攻击
A day marking the start of a large
对付美国与其盟帮
strike against the U.S. And her allies.
这应该是总统了
This should be the president now.
你有个艰巨的任务，宣科夫
You have a big job, Chenkov...
不过你行的
...but you can do it.
你还没告诉我，你的任务是什么
You still haven't told me what your job is.
家
Home.
我要回家
I'm going home.
-趴下！找掩护！ -保护总统
- Down! Take cover! - Get the president!
-有枪，他有枪  -退后！
- A gun! He's got a gun! - Get back!
退后！
Get back!
-你没事吧？  -没事
- Are you okay, sir? - Yes.
-该死   -依照程序，酋长前往地下碉堡
- Goddamn it. - Geronimo is SOP, downward mobile.
救命！这里！
Help, over here!
快叫医护人员
Get a medic! Get a medic!
我想我看到她了
I think I saw her.
你看到谁？
You saw who?
莎特
Salt.
我想我在走廊上看到她了
I think I saw her in the corridor.
另一位北约军官
The other NATO officer.
她在这里
She's here.
检查
Check.
-安全  -走
- Clear. - Move.
快！
Go!
我们看见第二位攻击者伊芙莎特
We may have a visual on a second assailant. Evelyn Salt.
重覆：伊芙莎特在警戒区内
Evelyn Salt on premises.
一身北约军官打扮
May be dressed as a NATO officer.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
白宫正遭受攻击
The White House is under attack.
请前往最近出口
If you are near an exit, please
立刻依序离开
proceed outside in an orderly manner.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
我要确保这条走廊安全无虞
I need this hallway cleared
to the left, now!
中心，请求启动地下碉堡
Command, this is Jenks. I need the PEOC bunker up and running.
这若是俄罗斯政府授权的行动
If this was authorised by the Russian government...
这就是战争行为，我们会复仇
...it is an act of war,and we will respond.
请前往最近出口
If you are near an exit, please
立刻依序离开
proceed outside in an orderly manner.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
-安全！  -走吧，长官
- Clear! - Let's go, sir.
A小队，行动
Alpha team!
快，快
Move, move.
关上
Close it.
立刻依序离开
Please proceed outside in an orderly manner.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
快，快
Go, go.
酋长五秒内抵达碉堡门口
Geronimo approaching bunker door in five seconds.
安全
Clear.
她会跟来吗？
Any chance she could follow?
门一关上，连我的人都进不来
My own men couldn't get through that door.
是啊，可惜她不是你的人
Yeah, well, unfortunately, she isn't one of yours.
好了，走
Okay, go.
等门关好再走
Stay until it's shut and sealed.
酋长安全
Geronimo secured.
-帮我接梅孚局长   -是，长官
- Get me Director Medford.- Yes, sir.
我想我们该严重考虑
Sir, I think we need to seriously consider the possibility...
今天，现在，就是毁灭日的开始
...that today, right now,could be the start of Day X.
总统先生，局长上线了
Mr. President,Director Medford is up.
玛莉安，情况如何？
Marion, what's the situation?
资料应该正显示在您的荧幕上
It should be coming up on one of your screens.
这里显示西伯利亚的移动飞弹
What you see there represents temperature drops...
温度下降
...in mobile missile units in Siberia.
这表示俄罗斯正在部署飞弹
It means the Russians are deploying their missiles to the field.
地面人员已确认此事，总统先生
And that's been confirmed on the ground, Mr. President.
我强烈建议提升战备到二级状态
Mr. President, I strongly recommend we go from DEFCON 4 to DEFCON 2.
至少在前线该如此
At least at our forward bases.
就这么办
Do it.
由于俄罗斯已部署飞弹
And since the Russians have deployed...
我们要考虑核子攻击的选项
...we need to look at our own nuclear attack options.
不认真考虑，就无法遏阻他们
It's not on the table, it's not a deterrent.
谢了，局长，我们会再和你联络
Thanks, Marion. We'll come back to you.
长官
Sir.
外门卡住了，没有反应
The outer portal door is jammed. No response.
大部分的监视器也失灵了
And we just lost the feed from most of our security cameras.
我们看不见，不过没人能进来
We're blind down here and no one can enter this facility.
中心，视讯无法传输
Command, our eyes are down.
地下碉堡安全外门也故障
We have a PEOC outer security door malfunction.
快点出去
Get out there now.
封住这个房间
Seal this room.
那条走廊，确认安全
Down that corridor. Secure it.
受害者被送往华盛顿医院
Victims are being tak en to George Washington Hospital.
据报白宫也有伤亡
Reports are coming in that there are casualties at the White House.
我是霍华路易斯总统
This is President Howard Lewis.
进行认证
- Proceed with authentication.
是，总统先生
- Yes, Mr. President.
-准备开始认证
-Z - Ready to commence authentication. - Zulu.
-T -E - Tango. - Echo.
-T  -E  - Tango.  - Echo.
-7月  -9日
- Seven. - Niner.
-J -X - Juliett. - X-ray.
-J  -X  - Juliett.  - X-ray.
-S -7 - Sierra. - Seven.
-S  -7  - Sierra.  - Seven.
-A -M - Alfa. - Mike.
-C -W - Charlie. - Whisky.
-5月 -6日
- Five.- Six.
T - Tango.
认证密码确认
- Authentication codes confirmed.
一切交给你了，总统先生
It's all yours now, Mr. President.
上帝与你同在
God be with you.
攻击选项和目标由您控制
Attack options and targeting under your control, Mr. President.
安德斯、纳布洛，你们在哪？
Anders and Nablo,what's your location?
门外的监视器还能用吗？接上来
Is the camera outside this door working? Put it up.
戴尔探员，报告情况
Officer Dryer,report situation.
戴尔探员，请说话
Officer Dryer, come in.
联邦通讯委员会启动紧急警报系统
Federal Communication Commission is activating the Emergency Alert System.
那是什么？
Who the hell's that?
是她
That's her.
是伊芙莎特
That's Evelyn Salt.
她突破了地堡1号
She's in. Go to DEFCON 1.
把你的枪给我，我会用枪
Give me your side arm.
不，总统身边只有特勤人员能持枪
No, sir. Only Secret Service possess firearms in the president's vicinity.
去他的规定，外面有敌人的特务
Screw protocol.We got an enemy agent.
规定就是规定
Protocol is protocol, sir.
死人就是死人
And dead is dead.
躲我后面
Behind me!
我是国家安全顾问
I'm the national security advisor.
再也不是了
Not anymore.
坐下
Sit down.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我的名字叫尼可莱塔寇夫斯基
My name, Mr. President,is Nikolai Tarkovsky.
照我说的去做
And unless you do exactly as I say...
否则我就是你最后看到的人
...I will be the last person you will ever see.
我们一起挑选攻击目标吧？
Shall we look at some selective attack options?
你去死吧
Go to hell.
攻击选项准备就绪
Selective attack options ready.
启动
泰德？
Ted?
紧急行动讯息…
Emergency action message released by...
恭喜，宣科夫同志，你成功了
Congratulations, Comrade Chenkov.You made it.
你怎么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
我试过很多次，不过
I tried many times, but...
我的孤独是我唯一的朋友
My loneliness was my only friend.
你没跟我们在一起  要不然我不会忘记你的
You weren't with us in Russia.I would have remembered you.
我比你早一期
I was a class ahead, comrade.
奥洛夫麾下最闪亮的星星
The brightest of any of Orlov's stars.
现在我很荣幸能发动攻击
And now it's my honour to launch the attack.
抱歉
Excuse me.
选择攻击目标
Selective attack targets acquired.
德黑兰
Tehran.
麦加
Mecca.
麦加？
Mecca?
德黑兰？
Tehran?
我们计划的第二步
Part two of our plan.
杀死九百万人
Kill nine million people.
激怒十亿穆斯林教徒
Enrage a billion Muslims.
美国会死得很难看
America will suffer a painful death.
行动许可连结
Permissive action links initiated.
(授权)
飞弹准备中
Missiles arming.
核武指挥权
Nuclear command...
移交空中
...posts airborne.
让我加入你吧
Let me join you.
洲际弹道飞弹设定
ICBMs set to...
最大破坏能量
...maximum yield.
你刚来到中情局时
You know, when you first came to Langley...
我没想到我能守住秘密
...I didn't think I'd be able to do it.
我没想到能够…
I didn't think I'd be able to...
抗拒吐露身分的诱惑
...resist the temptation to say something.
后来你认识了迈可
Then you met Mike and...
...然而...
...well...
结果情况改变了
...things changed.
让我加入你
Let me join you.
这些年来就在我眼前
All these years right in front of me
而我却完全不知道
and I never knew.
让我加入你
Let me join you.
我想跟你一起
I want to be with you.
(俄罗斯总统没死！)
众人都认为已死的人
The man we thought was dead has
奇迹似地复活了
made a resurrection that is miraculous.
马特维耶夫总统还活着
President Matveyev is alive.
您所看到的是俄罗斯现场传回
We're going to Russia. What you are seeing...
俄罗斯总统飞抵莫斯科
...are live pictures of Russian president Matveyev...
近郊机场的现场画面
...arriving at the airport outside of Moscow.
这太惊人了
This is astonishing.
据医生说，总统死亡的乌龙
According to his doctors, President Matveyev's mistak en death...
是由蜘蛛毒液萃取出的毒素
...is attributed to a temporary paralysis...
所引发的暂时性麻痹
...from a toxin derived from spider venom.
对那些...
A recap for those...
...谁可能不会关注当天的事件...
...who may not have been following the events of the day...
至少我没弄错
At least I was right.
我当时就觉得在北朝鲜已经失去你了
I had a feeling we'd lost you back there in North Korea.
我看得出迈可英勇的王子行动
I could see how moved you were
让你有多感动
by Mike's little white-knight routine.
你应该要招募他
You were supposed to recruit him, Ev...
不是爱上他
...not fall in love with him.
所以我叫奥洛夫去逮他
That's why I told Orlov to pick him up.
对了，迈可好吗？
By the way, how is Mike?
(重新确认身份)
请求确认身分
Identity confirmation requested.
身分确认
Identity confirmed.
义勇兵三型飞弹电力满载
Minuteman III ICBMs' batteries up to power.
授权99%
Authorisation, 99 percent.
快！
Go!
行动许可连结
Permissive action links initiated.
核子潜艇待命
Trident submarines at firing readiness.
请求许可发射
Permission to launch.
趴下，快！
Get down on the floor, now!
我叫你趴下！
I said now!
发射程序解除，系统回复
Launch sequence aborted.Systems restored.
-快，快，快 -把手举起来
- Move, move, move!- Show me your hands!
-要他们趴着 -手举起来
- Get down!- What is your name, sir?
-你是谁？ -我是中情局的温特，快救总统
I'm Theodore Winter, CIA.Help the president.
总统先生
Mr. President.
总统先生，你听得见吗？
Mr. President, can you hear me?
-别动 -急救小组马上到
- Hold still.- EMT's on the way.
送尸袋来，至少有七人死亡
Make sure they got body bags.At least seven.
她穿着防弹背心
She's wearing a vest.
五分钟后会议室见，我要清理一下
I'll meet you in five minutes.I wanna get cleaned up.
我要她单独关一间房
And I want her alone in a room.
我要她供出其他的俄国密探
If there are other KAs out there,I want her talking.
她不会说的
She won't talk.
她受过训练，无论如何都不会说
She's trained not to,no matter what we do to her.
我们要找这些人，就得自己找
If we're gonna find these people,we gotta do it.
我去整理一下，我马上回来
I'm gonna get cleaned up.I'll be right back.
总统安全前不得进出，请退后
No one comes through until the president is secure. Step back.
-我是温特  -退后，先生，请退后
- I'm Theodore Winter... - Step back, sir. Please.
你受伤了，坐下来吧？
Well, sir, you're injured. Why don't you have a seat?
我们会照顾你
We'll take a look at you.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
伤口很深
Pretty good gash there.
看来里面有玻璃
Looks like you got a piece of glass in there.
她又杀人了
She killed someone else.
是泰德温特，你最好快上来
It's Winter. It's Ted Winter, sir. You better get up here.
看看他，快看看他
Check him. Check him!
检查生命迹象
Checking vitals.
我摸不到脉搏
I'm not getting a pulse. I'm not getting much.
对于伊芙莎特，我们发现的越多   似乎知道的却越少
The more we find out about Evelyn Salt,the less we seem to know.The more we find out about Evelyn Salt,the less we seem to know.
可以确定的是她是个谜
She has proven a mystery.
我向美国国旗
I pledge allegiance to the flag...
以及共和国所代表的
...of the United States of America...
一个国家…
...and to the republic for which it stands...
宣誓效忠，在上帝…
...one nation, under God...
不可分割的自由…
...indivisible, with liberty...
与正义之下
...and justice for all.
百合折
The lily fold.
在我的新生命中   我试着减少功利想法
In my new life,I'm trying to be less utilitarian.
有人终止了导弹发射
Someone stopped the missile launch.
总统没有意识
所以不是你就是温特干的
President was unconscious,so it was either you or Winter.
总统说是温特开始的   所以…
President says Winter started it, so...
是你救了这个世界？
...you saved the world?
听好，莎特
Listen, Salt.
温特，我们可以找出源头
Winter we can figure out.
他过着生活，他留有痕迹
He led a life. He left a trail.
我们会回溯过去     必要的话我会解剖他
We'll trace it back.I will dissect him if I have to.
但是奥洛夫还在外面
But Orlov is still out there.
迈可常说最甜美的事…
Mike used to say the sweetest thing.
他常说他的心…
He used to say that his heart...
是张蜘蛛网
...was a spider web...
而我是在上面生活的蜘蛛
...and I was the spider who lived on top.
不论我在哪里    我都可以连着一条丝线…
And no matter where I was,I could attach a single thread...
这样我就永远都连系着
...so I would always be connected.
所以我永远可以找到回家的路
So I could always find my way home.
他告诉我无论何时     我看到一张蜘蛛网
He told me whenever I saw a spider web...
我就会记得他有多爱我
...I should remember how much he loved me.
我什么也没做
I did nothing.
他们杀了我丈夫而我只是看着     我什么事也没做
They killed my husband and I watched and I did nothing.
是为了大局着想
For the greater good.
我对迈可感到遗憾    不过奥洛夫…
I'm sorry about Mike, but Orlov...
-给我一点消息    -为什么？
- Give me something.- Why?
所以你就可以逮捕他？
So you can arrest him?
所以你的纳税人     可以把他放进一个美丽的小盒子里？
So your taxpayers can put him in a pretty little box?
他的真名不是奥洛夫
His real name is not Orlov.
那是什么？
What is it?
他们给我们这些牙齿
在后面…
They gave us these teeth in the back...
这就是我杀温特的原因
所以他不能自杀
It's why I killed Winter.So he couldn't do it himself.
该死！
Shit!
该死的氰化物
Goddamn cyanide.
对，是皮巴帝       直接把我接过去
Yeah, it's Peabody.Put me through straight away.
莎特刚刚想自杀，对
Salt just tried to kill herself. Yeah.
可能是氰化物
Could be cyanide.
要让她活着，各位
Keep her alive, folks.
不，他们现在正在想办法
No, they're trying to figure that out right now.
她的气管通畅吗？
Are her airways clear?
可恶
Shit.
别开枪…
Don't shoot, don't shoot.
站住！
Freeze!
我们的父亲决定…
Our father has decided that...
你们展开…
...the time has come...
全新生命的时间到了
...for you all to start your new lives.
准备我们的下一场攻击
To prepare for our next attack.
有什么是我可以效劳的吗？
Can I help you?
我的女儿
My daughter.
你是来亲吻戒指的吗？
Have you come to kiss the ring?
我是来告诉你我自由了
I've come to tell you that I'm free.